银翼杀手
二十一世纪初期  泰瑞公司
将机械人发展至连锁阶段
成为实际上和人类完全相同的生物  被称为复制人
连锁六型复制人  比创造他们的基因工程师们
有更优秀的力量及敏捷度  及不下于他们的智慧
复制人在世外殖民地  被当作奴工来使用
从事危险的探索与其他星球的殖民任务
一支连锁六型的战斗部队  在世外殖民地发动血腥叛变之后
复制人在地球被宣布为违法物  必须处以死刑
特种警察小组  银翼杀手部队
奉命一旦侦察到侵入的复制人
即可格杀勿论
这不称为处决  而是称为退役
洛杉矶  2019年11月
下一位  科沃斯基里昂
Next subject, Kowalski, Leon.
工程师  机器废物处理
Engineer, waste disposal.
第五区  新进人员  到职第六日
File section, New employee, six days.
请进
Come in.
坐下
Sit down.
我可以说话吗
Stand by for....
我接受测试时会有点紧张
I'm kind of nervous when I take tests.
好  请你别动
Just please don't move.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我今年已接受过智力测验  我不记得我测试过这些东西
I already had an IQ test. I don't think I've had one of these.
反应时间是评分项目之一  所以请专心
Reaction time is a factor, so pay attention.
现在  你回答的越快越好
Now answer as quickly as you can.
好的
Sure.
杭特华沙1187号
1187 at Hunterwasser.
-那是一间旅馆  -什么
-That's the hotel. -What?
-我住的地方  -环境不错吗
-Where I live. -Nice place?
对  当然  应该吧  这是测试的一部份
Yeah, sure, I guess. A part of the test?
不  只是热身
No. Just warming you up. That's all.
不是幻想之类的
it's not fancy or anything.
你在一处沙漠  在沙上独自行走  突然间
You're in a desert, walking along in the sand, when
-现在这是测试  -是的
-Is this the test now? -Yes.
你在一处沙漠  在沙地上独自行走
You're in a desert, walking along in the sand...
-突然间你往下一看  -哪一个
-when you look down. -What one?
-什么  -哪一个沙漠
-What? -What desert?
哪一个沙漠都没差别  这完全是假设
Doesn't make any difference. it's completely hypothetical.
-但是我为什么会在那里  -也许你受够了
-But how come I'd be there? -Maybe you're fed up.
也许你想独自一人  谁知道
Maybe you wanna be by yourself. Who knows?
你往下看  看见一只乌龟  里昂
You look down and see a tortoise. Leo.
-它向你爬过来  -乌龟  那是什么
-It's crawling towards you...-Tortoise? What's that?
-你知道海龟吧  -当然
-You know what a turtle is? -Of course.
同样的东西
Same thing.
我没看过海龟
I've never seen a turtle.
但是我明白你的意思
But I understand what you mean.
你伸手把乌龟翻过来  里昂
You reach down, you flip the tortoise over on its back, Leo.
这是你想出来的问题吗  贺登先生
Do you make up these questions, Mr. Holden?
还是他们写下来给你的
Or do they write them down for you?
乌龟腹部朝天躺着  肚子在烈阳下烤着
The tortoise lays on its back, its belly baking in the sun...
鼓动四肢想把自己翻过来  但没办法
beating its legs, trying to turn itself over, but it can't...
除非你肯帮忙  但是你不肯
not without your help. You're not helping.
-你说我不肯是什么意思  -就是说  你不肯帮忙
-What do you mean I'm not? -I mean you're not helping.
为什么会这样  里昂
Why is that, Leon?
这些只是问题  里昂
They're just questions, Leon.
回答你的问题  这些是他们写给我的
in answer to your query, they're written down for me.
这是个测试  设计来激发情绪反应
it's a test designed to provoke an emotional response.
我们可以继续吗
Shall we continue?
用一个单字形容  只形容你想到的优点
Describe in single words only the good things that come into your mind...
-关于你的母亲  -我母亲
-About your mother. -My mother?
是的
Yeah.
我来跟你说我的母亲吧
Let me tell you about my mother.
新生活就在世外殖民地正等着你
A new life awaits you in the Off-world colonels.
重新开始的机会
The chance to begin again
在充满机会与冒险的黄金之地
in a golden land of opportunity and adventure.
新生活就在世外殖民地正等着你
A new life awaits you in the Off-world colonels.
重新开始的机会
The chance to begin again...
在充满机会与冒险的黄金之地
in a golden land of opportunity and adventure.
给我四个
Give me four.
不  四个  二  二  四
No, four. Two, two. Four.
还有面
And noodles.
他说你被捕了  德卡先生
He says you under arrest, Mr. Deckard.
老兄  你找错人了
Got the wrong guy, pal.
他说你是银翼杀手
He say you Blade Runner.
告诉他我在吃东西
Tell him I'm eating.
布莱恩特  是吗
Bryant, huh?
黄色三号  爬升并维持高度4000
Yellow 3. Climb and maintain 4000.
当接近六号停机坪
When approach sixth transit
请谨慎小心
be cautious
最后降落
Final descent.
现在在降落航道  航向正确
Now on glide path. Mark course.
超过降落的入口
Over the landing threshold.
德卡
Hi ya, Deck.
布莱恩特
Bryant.
如果我只是叫你  你不会来的
You wouldn't have come if I just asked you to.
坐下  老兄
Sit down, pal.
别这么混账  德卡
Come on, don't be an asshole, Deckard.
有四个假货在街上闲晃
I've got four skin-jobs walking the streets.
他们劫持了世外殖民地的运输船  杀了乘客及船员
They jumped a shuttle Off-world, killed the crew and passengers.
两周前发现运输船在海岸飘流
They found the shuttle drifting off the coast two weeks ago...
所以他们就在附近
So we know they're around.
-真够丢脸  -不  一点都不丢脸
-Embarrassing. -No, sir, not embarrassing.
因为没有人会发现他们在这里
No one's ever gonna find out they're down here.
因为你会找到他们  而且你会把他们干掉
Because you're gonna spot them and air them out.
我不在这里上班了
I don't work here anymore.
-交给贺登吧  他很行  -我已经叫他去做了
-Give it to Holden. He's good. -I did.
现在他还能呼吸  只要没人拔他的呼吸机
He can breathe okay as long as nobody unplugs him.
他不够好  没你那么行
He's not good enough. Not good as you.
我需要你  德卡
I need you, Deck.
这事很棘手  是最棘手的
Now, this is a bad one, the worst yet.
我需要老的银翼杀手
I need the old Blade Runner.
我需要你的魔力
I need your magic.
我进来这儿之前就辞职了  布莱恩特
I was quit when I come in here, Bryant.
现在我更加不想干
I'm twice as quit now.
站住别动  你知道你的份量
Stop right where you are. You know the score, pal?
你不是警察  只是个小人物
If you're not cop, you're little people.
没得选择
No choice, huh?
没有选择  老兄
No choice, pal.
我今年已接受过智力测验
I already had an IQ test this year.
我不记得我测试过这些东西
I don't think I've ever had one of these.
反应时间是评分项目之一  所以请专心
Reaction time is a factor, so please pay attention.
-现在  你回答的越快越好  -好的
-Answer as quickly as you can. -Yeah, sure.
杭特华沙1187号
1187 at Hunterwasser.
-那是间旅馆  -什么
-Yeah. That's the hotel. -What?
-我住的地方  -环境不错吗
-Where I live. -Nice place?
对  我猜是的
Yeah, sure, I guess.
两周前有人从世外殖民地逃走
There was an escape from the Off-world coronels two weeks ago.
六个复制人  三男三女
Six Replicants, three male, three female.
屠杀23人  抢走了运输船
They slaughtered 23 people and jumped a shuttle.
空中巡逻队在海岸发现了运输船
An aerial patrol spotted the ship off the coast.
没有船员  不见他们踪影
No crew, no sight of them.
三天前夜里他们想闯入泰瑞公司
Three nights ago they tried to break into Tyrell Corporation.
其中两人想穿过电网给烧死
Two of them got fried running through an electrical field.
其他人不见了
We lost the others.
有可能他们想以雇员的身份潜入
On the possibility they might try to infiltrate as employees...
我叫贺登去对新的工人进行人性测验
I had Holden go over and run Voight-Kampff tests on the new workers.
看来他找到一个
Looks like he got himself one.
你往下看  看见一只乌龟  里昂
So you look down and you see a tortoise. It's crawling towards you.
那是里昂
That's Leon.
设计来跨星际运输军火
Ammunition loader on intergalactic runs.
他能日以继夜的扛着400磅的货物行进
He can lift 400-pound atomic loads all day and night.
能伤到他的唯一办法就是杀了他
The only way you can hurt him is to kill him.
我不懂  为何他们冒险回来地球
I don't get it. What do they risk coming back to Earth for?
这太不寻常了  为什么
That's unusual. Why?
他们想从泰瑞公司得到什么
What do they want out of the Tyrell Corporation?
老兄  别问我  这就是找你来的原因
Well, you tell me, pal. That's what you're here for.
-这是什么  -连锁六型
-What's this? -Nexus 6. Roy Batty.
罗伊贝逖  启动日期  2016年
Incept date, 2016.
战斗型号  能最佳化的自给自足
Combat model. Optimum self-sufficiency.
大概是领导人
Probably the leader.
这是卓拉
This is Zhora.
她被训练成为世外殖民地的刺客
She's trained for an Off-world kick murder squad.
说到美女与野兽
Talk about Beauty and the Beast.
她两者皆是
She's both.
第四个假货是蒲莉丝  是基本娱乐型号
The fourth skin-job is Pris, a basic pleasure model.
外围殖民地军事俱乐部的标准装备
The standard item for military clubs in the outer coronels.
他们各方面都是设计来模仿人类  除了他们的感情
They were designed to copy human beings in every way except their emotions.
但设计者认为数年后
The designers reckoned after a few years...
他们可能会发展出自己的情绪反应
they might develop their own emotional responses.
仇恨  爱  恐惧  愤怒  羡慕
Oh, hate, love, fear, anger, envy.
-所以他们做了保险装置  -是什么
-So they built in a fall-safe device. -Which is what?
四年的寿命
-Four-year lifespan.
现在泰瑞公司有一个连锁六型
Now, there's a Nexus 6 over at the Tyrell Corporation.
我要你过去用机器测试看看
I want you to go put the machine on it.
要是机器测不出来呢
And if the machine doesn't work?
喜欢这只猫头鹰吗
Do you like our owl?
是人造的
It's artificial?
当然
Of course it is.
一定很贵
Must be expensive.
非常贵  我叫瑞秋
Very. I'm Rachael.
德卡
Deckard.
看来你认为我们的产品对大众无益
it seems you feel our work is not a benefit to the public.
复制人就像其他的机器  不是有益便是有危险
Replicants are like any other machine, They're either a benefit or a hazard.
若他们有益  则和我无关
if they're a benefit, it's not my problem.
我可问你一个私人问题吗
May I ask you a personal question?
当然
Sure.
你是否曾经错误地把人类退役
Have you ever retired a human by mistake?
没有
No.
但以你的职位  那是种风险
But in your position, that is a risk.
这是移情测试吗
Is this to be an empathy test?
所谓脸红反应的微血管扩张
Capillary dilation of the so-called blush response?
瞳孔的波动
Fluctuation of the pupil.
虹膜不自觉地扩大
Involuntary dilation of the iris.
我们简称为人性测验
We call it Voight-Kampff for short.
德卡先生  艾登泰瑞博士
Mr. Deckard, Dr. Eldon Tyrell.
示范一下
Demonstrate it.
-我想看看它的运作  -测试对象在哪
-I wanna see it work. -Where's the subject?
我想看它用来测试人类
I wanna see it work on a person.
在看是的结果之前  我想看否的情况
I wanna see a negative before I provide you with a positive.
那能证明什么
What's that gonna prove?
让我满足
Indulge me.
测试你
On you?
测试她
Try her.
这里太亮了
It's too bright in here.
介意我抽烟
Do you mind if I smoke?
对测试没影响
it won't affect the test.
好  我会问你一连串的问题
All right, I'm gonna ask you a series of questions.
你只需放松  尽量简洁地回答
Just relax and answer them as simply as you can.
在你生日那天  有人给你送牛皮皮夹
it's your birthday. Someone gives you a calfskin wallet.
我不会接受
I wouldn't accept it.
同时我会向警方举报送给我的人
Also, I'd report the person who gave it to me to the police.
你有一个小男孩  他给你看他的蝴蝶标本收藏
You've got a little boy. He shows you his butterfly collection...
和杀昆虫的酒精瓶
plus the killing jar.
我会带他看医生
I'd take him to the doctor.
你在看电视
You're watching television.
忽然发觉手臂上有一只黄蜂
Suddenly you realize there's a wasp crawling on your arm.
我会杀了它
I'd kill it.
你在看杂志
You're reading a magazine.
看见一幅全页的女人裸照
You come across a full-page nude photo of a girl.
这是测试我是复制人还是女同性恋者  德卡先生
Is this testing whether I'm a Replicant or a lesbian, Mr. Deckard?
请回答问题
Just answer the questions, please.
你把它拿给丈夫看
You show it to your husband.
他很喜欢  所以把它挂在你们卧室墙上
He likes it so much he hangs it on your bedroom wall.
我不会让他挂
I wouldn't let him.
-为什么  -他有我应该就够了
-Why not? -I should be enough for him.
再问一题
One more question.
你观赏一出舞台剧  正进行一场宴会
You're watching a stage play, a banquet is in progress.
宾客享用生蚝作开胃菜
The guests are enjoying an appetizer of raw oysters.
主菜包括炖狗肉
The entre consists of boiled dog.
你可否出去一会儿  瑞秋
Would you step out for a few moments, Rachael?
谢谢
Thank you.
-她是复制人  对吧  -我很佩服
-She's a Replicant, isn't she? -I'm impressed.
通常要问多少问题才会发现
How many questions does it usually take to spot one?
-我不懂  泰瑞  -多少个问题
-I don't get it, Tyrell. -How many questions?
20到30个互相对照的问题
Twenty, thirty, cross-referenced.
瑞秋问了超过一百个吧
It took more than a hundred for Rachael, didn't it?
她不知道
She doesn't know.
我想  她开始怀疑了
She's beginning to suspect, I think.
怀疑  它怎会不知道自己是什么
Suspect ? How can it not know what it is
在泰瑞  商业是我们的目标
Commerce is our goal here at Tyrell.
比人类更像人类是我们的座右铭
More human than human is our motto.
瑞秋是个实验  如此而已
Rachael is an experiment, nothing more.
我们开始认同他们
We began to recognize in them
这是种怪异的妄想
a strange obsession.
毕竟他们缺乏情感经验
After all, they are emotionally inexperienced, with only a few years...
只有几年的时间去累积
in which to store up the experiences
你我视为理所当然的体验  如果我们赐予他们过去
which you and I take for granted if we gift them a past,
创造出他们情感上的依靠和安慰
we create a cushion...or a pillow for their emotions and
结果是我们更能够控制他们
then consequently we can control them better.
记忆
Memories.
你说的是记忆
You're talking about memories.
反应时间是评分项目之一  所以请专心
Reaction time is a factor, so please pay attention.
-现在  你回答的越快越好  -好的
-Now answer as quickly as you can. -Sure.
杭特华沙1187号
-1187 at Hunterwasser.
-那是一间旅馆  -什么
-What? -Yeah. That's the hotel.
-我住的地方  -环境不错吗
-Where I live. -Nice place?
对  当然  应该吧  这是测试的一部份吗
Yeah, sure, I guess. Is that part of the test?
不是
No.
科沃斯基
Kowalski.
时间
Time...
够了
enough.
你拿到你宝贵的照片了
Did you get your precious photos?
有人在
Someone was there.
人
Men?
警察
Policemen?
天使如火般地坠落
Fiery the angels fell
海岸四处咆哮着雷声
Deep thunder rolled around their shores
燃烧着海兽的火焰
Burning with the fires of Orca
你不能来这里
You not come here!
非法入侵
Illegal!
很冷的  那是我的眼睛  会冻伤的
Cold! Those are my eyes! Freezing!
是的
Yes.
问题
Questions.
型号  寿命  启动日期
Morphology. longevity. Incept dates.
不知道  我不知道这些东西
Don't know. I don't know such stuff.
我只做眼睛
I just do eyes.
只有眼睛  只是基因设计
Just eyes, just genetic design.
只有眼睛
Just eyes.
你是连锁型的
You Nexus, huh?
我设计了你的眼睛
I design your eyes.
老周
Chew...
但愿你能目睹我用你的眼睛所看见的
If only you could see what I've seen with your eyes.
现在
Now...
问题
questions.
我不知道答案
I don't know answers.
谁知道
Who does?
泰瑞  他无所不知
Tyrell. He knows everything.
泰瑞公司
Tyrell Corporation?
他是大老板  大天才  他设计了你的心智
He big boss. Big genius. He design your mind.
你的脑袋
Your brain, huh?
聪明
Smart.
很冷
Very cold.
要见他不容易
Not an easy man to see...
把外套给我
Give me coat.
是吗
I guess?
赛巴斯汀
Sebastian.
他能带你去那里  他能带你去那里
He takes you there. He takes you there.
哪个赛巴斯汀
Sebastian who?
J  J.F.
J.F...
赛巴斯汀
...Sebast...
那么
Now...
我们可以在哪里找到这位
where...would we find this
J. F. 赛巴斯汀
J.F. Sebastian?
我们可以继续吗
Let's continue, shall we?
用一个单字形容
Describe in single words...
只形容你想到的优点
only the good things that come into your mind
关于你的母亲
about your mother.
-我母亲  -是的
-My mother? -Yeah.
我来跟你说我的母亲吧
I'll tell you about my mother.
声纹辨织  请说出你楼层号码
Voice print identification. Your floor number, please.
-德卡  97  -97  谢谢
-Deckard, 97. -97. -Thank you. Danke.
我想见你
I wanted to see you.
所以我在这里等  让我帮你
So I waited. Let me help you.
我为何需要帮忙
What do I need help for?
我不知道为什么他告诉你  他所做的
I don't know why he told you what he did.
去跟他谈
Talk to him.
他不会见我
He wouldn't see me.
想喝酒吗
You want a drink?
不
No?
你认为我是复制人  是吧
You think I'm a Replicant, don't you?
看着
Look.
这是我和我母亲
It's me with my mother.
是吗
Yeah?
记得你六岁的时候吗
Remember when you were 6?
你和哥哥从地下室窗户溜进空的大楼
You and your brother snuck into an empty building through a basement window.
你们玩扮医生游戏
You were gonna play doctor?
他给你看他下面  但轮到你时  你害怕然后跑走了
He showed you his, and when it got to be your turn, you chickened and ran.
记得吗
Remember that?
你有对任何人说吗  你母亲  泰瑞  其他人
Did you ever tell anybody that? Your mother, Tyrell, anybody, huh?
记得住在你窗外树丛的蜘蛛吗
You remember the spider that lived in the bush outside your window?
橙色身体  绿色的脚
Orange body, green legs?
看着它织网织了整个夏天  有一天  上面有个巨卵
Watched her build a web all summer?
卵孵化了
The egg hatched... .
-卵孵化了  -然后呢
-The egg hatched... -And?
有一百只小蜘蛛爬出来
And a hundred baby spiders came out.
它们把它吃了
And they ate her.
植入
Implants.
那不是你的回忆  是别人的
Those aren't your memories, they're somebody else's.
那是泰瑞的侄女的回忆
They're Tyrell's niece's.
好吧  糟糕的笑话
Okay. Bad joke.
我说了个糟糕的笑话  你不是复制人
I made a bad joke. You're not a Replicant.
回家去  好吗
Go home. Okay
是真的  我很抱歉
No, really. I'm sorry.
回家吧
Go home.
想喝一杯吗
Want a drink?
我给你来杯酒  我给你个杯子
I'll get you a drink. I'll get a glass.
你忘了你的袋子
You forgot your bag.
我迷路了
I'm lost.
放心  我不会伤害你的
Don't worry, I won't hurt you.
-你叫什么  -蒲莉丝
-What's your name? -Pris.
我叫J.F.赛巴斯汀
Mine's J.F. Sebastian.
你要去哪
Oh, where were you going?
回家
Home?
我没有家
I don't have one.
我们吓了对方一跳  是吧
We scared each other pretty good, didn't we?
当然
We sure did.
我好饿  J.F.
I'm hungry, J.F.
我里面有食物  你要进来吗
I got stuff inside. You wanna come in?
我正希望你这么说
I was hoping you'd say that.
你一个人住在这里
Do you live in this building all by yourself?
对  现在我确实是一个人住在这里
Yeah, I live here pretty much alone right now.
这里不缺住的地方
No housing shortage around here.
每个人都有很多空间
Plenty of room for everybody.
小心有水
Watch out for the water.
你在这里一定很寂寞  J.F.
Must get lonely here, J.F.
不算是  我制造朋友
Not really. I make friends.
他们是玩具  我的朋友是玩具  他们是我做的
They're toys. My friends are toys. I make them.
是个嗜好  我是基因设计师  你知道那是什么吗
it's a hobby. I'm a genetic designer. You know what it is?
不知道
No.
现在
Now.
我回来了
Yoo-hoo, home again.
-晚安  J.F.  -晚安  各位
-Good evening, J.F. -Evening, fellas.
他们是我朋友  是我做的
They're my friends. I made them.
你的家人呢
Where are your folks?
我算是个孤儿
I'm sort of an orphan.
那你的朋友呢
What about your friends?
我有一些  但我必需要找到他们
I have some, but I have to find them.
明天我会告诉他们我在哪里
I'll let them know where I am tomorrow.
我可以帮你拿这些东西吗  湿透了  不是吗
Can I take those things for you? They're soaked, aren't they?
放大224到176
Enhance 224 to 176.
放大  停
Enhance. Stop.
推入
Move in.
停
Stop.
拉出  右移  停
Pull out, track right. Stop.
置中  拉回
Center and pull back.
停
Stop.
移动右45
Track 45 right.
停
Stop.
置中然后停
Center and stop.
放大34至36
Enhance 34 to 36.
右移和拉回
Pan right and pull back.
停
Stop.
放大34至46
Enhance 34 to 46.
拉回
Pull back.
慢着  向右
Wait a minute. Go right.
停
Stop.
放大57至19
Enhance 57-19.
移动左45
Track 45 left.
停
Stop.
放大15至23
Enhance 15 to 23.
这儿给我一份复印
Give me a hard copy right there.
鱼吗
Fish?
我看这是制造的  看
I think it was manufactured locally.
手工精细  品质优良
Finest quality. Superior workmanship.
有制作者的序号
There is the maker's serial number.
990-6947
9906947.
XB-71
很有趣
Interesting.
这不是鱼  是蛇的鳞片
Not fish. Snake scale.
蛇
Snake.
找阿布杜尔哈桑  这蛇是他做的
Try Abdul Ben Hassan. He make this snake!
阿布杜尔哈桑
Abdul Hassan?
我是警察  想问你几个问题
I'm a police officer. I'd like to ask you a few questions.
人造蛇执照XB-71  是你吗
Artificial snake license XB71, that's you?
这是你的作品  你卖给了谁
This is your work, huh? Who did you sell it to?
我的作品  没多少人付得起这样的品质
My work? Not too many could afford such quality.
-有多少  -很少
-How many? -Very few.
是多少  搞清楚  老兄
How few? Look, my friend
塔菲刘易斯  在第四区  唐人街
Taffey Lewis'. Down in the Fourth Sector. Chinatown.
尽快通过
Cross now. Cross now.
酒保
Bartender.
塔菲刘易斯
Taffey Lewis?
多谢
Thank you.
塔菲
Taffey?
-我想问你几个问题  -问吧
-I'd like to ask you a few questions. -Blow.
你有向埃及人买过蛇吗  塔菲
You ever buy snakes from the Egyptian, Taffey?
经常买  老兄
All the time, pal.
见过这女孩吗
You ever see this girl, huh?
没见过  快滚
Never seen her. Buzz off.
你的执照还有效吗  老兄
Your licenses in order, pal?
路易  这位仁兄口渴
Hey, Louie. The man is dry.
免费给他一杯  好吗  再见
Give him one on the house, okay? See.
喂
Hello?
以前是有人离开过我  但是
I've had people walk out on me before, but not when...
都不是我那么迷人的时候
I was being so charming.
我现在在第四区的酒吧
I'm in a bar, here now, down in the Fourth Sector.
塔菲刘易斯这里
Taffey Lewis is on the line.
你何不来这里喝一杯
Why don't you come on down here and have a drink?
我不这么想  德卡先生
I don't think so, Mr. Deckard.
-那不是我去的地方  -那到别处去
-That's not my kind of place. -Go someplace else
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen...
塔菲刘易斯巨献  莎乐美小姐与蛇共舞
Taffey Lewis presents Miss Salome and the snake.
看她与曾使人堕落的蛇
Watch her take the pleasure from the serpent...
尽情享受欢愉
that once corrupted man.
对不起 莎乐美小姐  我可跟你谈一下吗
Excuse me, Miss Salome, can I talk to you for a minute?
我是美国综艺艺人协会的
I'm from the American Federation of Variety Artists.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我不是来此请你加入的
I'm not here to make you join.
不  女士  那不是我的部门
No, ma'am. That's not my department.
事实上
Actually...
我是道德凌虐秘密委员会的人
I'm from the Confidential Committee on Moral Abuses.
-道德凌虐委员会  -是的  女士
-Committee of Moral Abuses? -Yes, ma'am.
据报这儿的管理阶层
There's been reports that the management...
曾经侵犯过艺人
has been taking liberties with the artists.
我完全不知道
I don't know nothing about it.
你可有在任何方面感到被剥削
Have you felt yourself to be exploited in any way?
你指的剥削是什么意思
How do you mean exploited?
像是要得到这份工作
Well, like to get this job.
我是说  你是否  你是否有做或是被要求做任何
I mean, did you do, or were you asked to do, anything that's...
猥亵或令人厌恶的事
lewd or unsavory or...
不做的话就把你开除
otherwise repulsive to your person, huh?
-你是当真的  -是的
-Are you for real? -Oh, yeah.
我想  想检查你的更衣室  如果可以的话
I'd like to check your dressing room, if I may.
-要做什么  -要找看看  有没有洞
-For what? -For holes.
洞
Holes?
你一定很吃惊
Well, you'd be surprised what a guy would go through...
有人会不择手段为了偷瞄动人的身体
to get a glimpse of a beautiful body.
不  我不惊讶
No, I wouldn't.
小的
little...
肮脏的洞  他们在墙上钻孔好偷看女人脱衣服
dirty holes they drill in the wall so they can watch a lady undress.
-这蛇是真的吗  -当然不是真的
-Is this a real snake? -Of course it's not real.
如果我买得起真蛇  还会在这儿工作吗
Think I'd be working in a place like this if I could afford a real snake?
那么  要是有人想剥削我  我该找谁
So if somebody does try to exploit me, who do I go to about it?
-找我  -你这人真是勤奋  帮我擦干
-Me. -You're a dedicated man. Dry me.
尽快通过
Cross now. Cross now.
不准通过  不准通过
Don't walk. Don't walk.
尽速通过
Cross now. Cross now.
让开  别挡路
Move! Get out of the way!
德卡
Deckard.
B-263-54
B26354.
散开  散开
Move on. Move on.
等一下
A minute.
-你要什么  -青岛
-Yeah, what do you want? -Tsingtao.
-这些够吗  -够
-This enough? -Yeah.
布莱恩特
Bryant.
老天  德卡
Christ, Deckard,
你看起来和你丢在路边的那个假货一样糟糕
You look almost as bad as that skin-job you left on the sidewalk.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
你可向他学着点  加夫
Could learn from this guy, Gaff.
天杀的  他根本就是单人屠宰场
He's a goddamn one-man slaughterhouse, that's what he is.
还有四个  加夫  我们走吧
Four more to go. Come on, Gaff, let's go.
三个
Three.
-还有三个  -是四个
-There's three to go. -There's four.
还有你在泰瑞公司测试的那个假货
That skin-job you VK'd at the Tyrell Corporation...
瑞秋失踪了  消失不见
Rachael, disappeared, vanished.
她甚至不知道自己是个复制人
Didn't even know she was a Replicant.
泰瑞说是和大脑植入有关
Something to do with a brain implant, says Tyrell.
走吧  加夫  替我喝一杯吧  老兄
Come on, Gaff. Drink some for me, huh, pal?
-里昂  -我几岁了
-Leon. -How old am I?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的生日是2017年4月10日  我能活多久
My birthday's April 10, 2017. How long do I live?
四年
Four years.
比你还久
More than you.
活在恐惧中是很痛苦的  不是吗
Painful to live in fear, isn't it?
没什么比永远搔不到的痒更惨的事
Nothing is worse than having an itch you can never scratch.
我同意
I agree.
醒来  该受死了
Wake up. Time to die.
发抖
Shakes?
我也是
Me too.
我抖的厉害
I get them bad.
这是这工作的一部份
It's part of the business.
我不是做这工作的
I'm not in the business.
我就是这工作
I am the business.
要是我往北走呢
What if I go north?
消失不见
Disappear.
你是否会来追我
Would you come after me?
猎杀我
Hunt me?
不
No.
我不会
No, I wouldn't.
我欠你一次
I owe you one.
但别人会追你
But somebody would.
德卡
Deckard...
你知道我的档案
You know those files on me?
启动日期
The incept date.
寿命  诸如此类的事情
The longevity. Those things.
你看过
You saw them?
那些是机密
They're...classified.
但你是个警察
But you're a policeman.
我没有看
I...didn't look at them.
你知道  你那个人性测验
You know, that Voight-Kampff test of yours...
你曾经用来测试你自己吗
did you ever take that test yourself?
德卡
Deckard.
我梦到音乐
I dreamt music.
我不知道我会不会弹琴
I didn't know if I could play.
我记得上过课
I remember lessons.
我不知道那是我  还是泰瑞的侄女
I don't know if it's me or Tyrell's niece.
你弹得很美
You play beautifully.
现在  吻我
Now you kiss me.
-我不能依靠我的记  -说  吻我
-I can't rely on my...-Say, Kiss me.
吻我
Kiss me.
我要你
I want you.
再说一次
Again.
我要你
I want you.
拥抱我
Put your hands on me.
-你做什么  -对不起  看看而已
-What you doing? -I'm sorry. Just peeking.
-我看来如何  -好一点
-How do I look? -You look better.
-只是好一点  -你看来很漂亮
-Just better? -Well...you look beautiful.
谢谢
Thanks.
你几岁了
How old are you?
二十五
Twenty-five.
-你有什么问题  -麦修撒拉征候群
-What's your problem? -Methuselah syndrome.
那是什么
What's that?
我的腺体  变老的太快
My glands, they grow old too fast.
这是你还留在地球的原因
Is that why you're still on Earth?
对  我没法通过体检
Yeah. I couldn't pass the medical.
反正  我满喜欢待在这里
Anyway...I kind of like it here.
我喜欢你现在的样子
I like you...just the way you are.
洛伊
Hi, Roy.
老天  你的玩具真的很不错
Hi. Gosh, you really get some nice toys here.
这就是我对你说过的朋友
This is the friend I was telling you about.
这是我的救星  J.F.赛巴斯汀
This is my savior, J.F. Sebastian.
赛巴斯汀
Sebastian.
我喜欢留下不走的人
I like a man that stays put.
你一个人住在这里  是吗
You live here all by yourself, do you?
是的
Yes.
要不要吃早餐
How about some breakfast?
我去煮早餐  失陪
I was just gonna make some. Excuse me.
怎样
Well?
-里昂  -怎么了
-Leon...-What's going on?
我
I...
现在只有我们俩了
There's only two of us now.
我们太笨了  我们会死的
Then we're stupid and we'll die.
不  不会的
No, we won't.
不  马吃掉皇后
No. Knight takes queen, see
我不会这样下
Won't do.
你为何盯着我们看  赛巴斯汀
Why are you staring at us, Sebastian?
因为  你这么独特
Because...you're so different.
你是这么的完美
You're so perfect.
是的
Yes.
你是哪一代的
What generation are you?
-连锁六型  -我就知道
-Nexus 6. -I knew it.
因为我替泰瑞公司做的基因设计
'Cause I do genetic design work for the Tyrell Corporation.
你有我的一部份
There's some of me in you.
秀给我看
Show me something.
-像什么  -什么都行
-like what? -like anything.
我们不是电脑  赛巴斯汀  我们是血肉之躯
We're no computers, Sebastian. We're physical.
我思考  赛巴斯汀  故我在
I think, Sebastian...therefore, I am.
非常好  蒲莉丝  现在让他看看为什么
Very good, Pris. Now show him why.
-我们有许多共通点  -你是什么意思
-We've got a lot in common. -What do you mean?
-类似的问题  -加速衰老
-Similar problems. -Accelerated decrepitude.
我对生化机械所知不多  洛伊  我希望我知道
I don't know much about bio-mechanics, Roy. I wish I did.
要是我们不尽快找出办法
if we don't find help soon...
蒲莉丝就活不久了
Pris hasn't got long to live.
我们不能容许它发生
We can't allow that.
-他厉害吗  -谁
-Is he good? -Who?
-你的对手  -泰瑞博士
-Your opponent. -Oh, Dr. Tyrell?
我下棋只击败他一次  他是个天才
I've only beaten him once in chess. He's a genius.
你是他设计的
He designed you.
也许他能帮忙
Maybe he could help.
我很乐意向他提出
I'd be happy to mention it to him.
最好是我能亲自和他谈
Better if I talk to him in person.
就我所知  要见他不太容易
But I understand he's a sort of hard man to get to.
是的  很难
Yes. Very.
你会帮我们吗
Will you help us?
我不能
I can't.
我们需要你  赛巴斯汀
We need you, Sebastian.
你是我们最好的  唯一的朋友
You're our best and only friend.
我们好高兴你找到我们
We're so happy you found us.
我不认为世上有其他人类会帮助我们
I don't think there's another human being in the whole world would help us.
六万六千 普塞与安高比
66,000 Prosser & Ankovich.
卖出  卖出价
Trade. Trade at two.
蓝色入口
Blue entry.
J.F.赛巴斯汀先生
A Mr. J.F. Sebastian.
1-6-4-1-7
16417.
在这个时候
At this hour?
有何贵干  赛巴斯汀
What can I do for you, Sebastian?
皇后吃掉象六  将军
Queen to bishop six. Check.
乱来
Nonsense.
等一等
Just a moment.
皇后吃掉象六  荒谬
Queen to bishop six, ridiculous.
皇后
Queen...
象六
Bishop six.
马
Knight...
吃掉皇后
takes queen.
你想到了什么  赛巴斯汀
What's on your mind, Sebastian?
你在想什么
What are you thinking about
象移到国王七  将军
Bishop to king seven. Checkmate.
我看是象移到国王七  将军
Bishop to king seven. Checkmate, I think.
你思潮泉涌了吗  赛巴斯汀
Got a brainstorm, huh, Sebastian?
牛奶和饼干让你睡不着
Milk and cookies kept you awake, huh?
我们来讨论一下
Let's discuss this.
你还是上来吧  赛巴斯汀
You better come up, Sebastian.
泰瑞先生
Mr. Tyrell?
我
I...
我带了个朋友
I brought a friend.
我很惊讶你没有早点来
I'm surprised you didn't come here sooner.
一个人要见造物者并不容易
it's not an easy thing to meet your maker.
造物者能为你做什么吗
And what can he do for you?
造物者能否修理他所造之物
Can the maker repair what he makes?
你想  被修改吗
Would you like to be modified?
留在这里
Stay here.
我想的是更根本的事
Had in mind something a little more radical.
什么
What?
-有什么问题  -死亡
-What seems to be the problem? -Death.
死亡
Death.
恐怕这有点超出了我的管辖范围  你
Well, I'm afraid that's a little out of my jurisdiction. You...
我要更多的生命  父亲
I want more life...father.
生命的真相
The facts of life.
想要改变
To make an alteration in the...
有机生物系统的进化是会致命的
evolvement of an organic life system is fatai.
编码程序一旦建立便无法修改
A coding sequence cannot be revised once it's been established.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为  在温育的第二天
Because by the second day of incubation...
任何细胞进行逆转的突变
any cells that have undergone reversion mutations...
会产生回复突变的菌落  就像老鼠离开一艘船
give rise to revertant colonels like rats leaving a sinking ship.
然后船沉没
Then the ship sinks.
那EMS重组呢
What about EMS recombination?
我们试过了
We've already tried it.
甲乙基烷矿酸是烷化剂
Ethyl methane suffocate is an alkyiating agent and a potent mutagen.
也是有效的突变剂  它创造出非常致命的病毒
It created a virus so lethal the...
实验对象离开实验台前就死了
subject was dead before he left the table.
抑制蛋白可阻挡运作的细胞
Then a repressor protein that blocks the operating cells.
它不会阻碍复制  但会导致复制错误
Wouldn't obstruct replication, but it does give rise to an error in replication.
因此  新形成的DNA带有变异
So that the newly formed DNA strand carries a mutation...
你会再次得到病毒
and you've got a virus again.
但这些  所有的一切都只是
But this, all of this, is...
理论
academic.
我们已尽我们所能把你做好
You were made as well as we could make you.
但不能持久
But not to last.
两倍明亮的光芒  只能燃烧一半的寿命
The light that burns twice as bright burns half as long.
而你燃烧得非常耀眼  罗伊
And you have burned so very, very brightly, Roy.
看看你  你是天之骄子
Look at you. You're the prodigal son.
你是个了不得的恩赐
You're quite a prize.
我做过  可议的事
I've done...questionable things.
同时  也是不平凡的事
Also extraordinary things.
享受你剩下的时间吧
Revel in your time.
你想生化机械之主会让你上天堂吗
Nothing the god of biomechanics wouldn't let you in heaven for.
抱歉  赛巴斯汀
Sorry, Sebastian.
来吧  来吧
Come. Come.
和泰瑞一起的尸体是25岁的白种男性
Body identified with Tyrell is a 25-year-old male Caucasian.
姓名  赛巴斯汀  J.F.赛巴斯汀
Name, Sebastian, J.F. Sebastian.
地址  布拉德柏利公寓大厦
Address, Bradbury Apartments,
第九区  N.F.46751
Ninth Sector, NF4675 1.
我要你过去那里
I want you to go down there and
本区地面交通封闭  你在这里做什么
This sector's closed to ground traffic. What're you doing here?
-我在工作  你要做什么  -我现在要逮捕你
-I'm working. What are you doing? -Arresting you, that's what I'm doing.
我是德卡  银翼杀手  2-63-54
I'm Deckard, Blade Runner. 26354.
我已备案及接受监督
I'm filed and monitored.
等等  正在查
Hold on. Checking.
好  确认无误  祝好运
Okay. Checked and cleared. Have a better one.
-喂  -嗨  J.F.在吗
-Hello. -Hi. is J.F. there?
-你是哪位  -艾迪  J.F.的老朋友
-Who is it? -This is Eddie, old friend of J.F.'s.
这可不是对待朋友之道
That's no way to treat a friend.
晚安  J.F.
Good evening, J.F.
茶
Tea
更多茶
More tea
茶
Tea
更多茶
More tea
茶
Tea
更多茶
More tea
向手无寸铁的对手开枪可不太光明正大
Not very sporting to fire on an unarmed opponent.
我以为你应该是个好人
I thought you were supposed to be good.
你不是好人吗
Aren't you the good man?
来吧  德卡
Come on, Deckard.
让我看看
Show me...
你有多少能耐
What you're made of.
为自己骄傲吗  小个子
Proud of yourself, little man?
这是为了卓拉
This is for Zhora.
这是为蒲莉丝
This is for Pris.
来吧  德卡
Come on, Deckard.
我就在这里  但你要射直一点
I'm right here, but you've gotta shoot straight.
射直似乎还不够好  现在轮到我了
Straight doesn't seem to be good enough! Now it's my turn.
我来之前会给你几秒钟的时间
I'm gonna give you a few seconds before I come.
一  二
One. Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
蒲莉丝
Pris.
我来了
I'm coming.
德卡
Deckard!
四  五
Four, five
要如何活下来
How to stay allve?
我看到你了
I can see you!
德卡  还不行
Not yet!
不
Not... .
五
Five
对了
Yes.
你最好振作一点
You better get it up.
不然我要杀了你
Or I'm gonna have to kill you.
要是你死了  你就没法玩了  如果你不玩
Unless you're alive, you can't play. And if you don't play .
六  七
Six, seven
下地狱或上天堂
Go to hell or go to heaven
很好  就是这种精神
Good, that's the spirit!
好痛
That hurt.
你真不理智
That was irrational of you.
更不用说  毫无运动精神
Not to mention...unsportsmanlike.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
活在恐惧中的体验还不错吧
Quite an experience to live in fear, isn't it?
这就是做奴隶的滋味
That's what it is to be a slave.
我所见过的事物
I've...
你们人类绝对无法置信
seen things you people wouldn't believe.
我目睹战船在猎户星座的端沿起火燃烧
Attack ships on fire off the shoulder of Orion.
我看着C射线
I watched C-beams...
在唐怀瑟之门附近的黑暗中闪耀
glitter in the dark near the Tanah user Gate.
所有这些  时刻终将流失
All those...moments will be lost
在时光中
in time...
一如眼泪
like...tears
消失在雨中
in rain.
死亡的时刻到了
Time to die.
你完成了男人的工作  阁下
You've done a man's job, sir.
我猜你做完了
I guess you're through, huh?
完成了
Finished.
可惜她活不成了
it's too bad she won't live.
可是  谁能呢
But then again, who does?
瑞秋
Rachael?
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
我爱你
I love you.
你信任我吗
Do you trust me?
我信任你
I trust you.
瑞秋
Rachael?
可惜她活不成了
It's too bad she won't live.
可是  谁能呢
But then again, who does?